Matthew Grossman

508-614-0979 / grossmanmatt@yahoo.com / github.com/mbgrossm2009/ www.mattgrossman.net

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Entry Level Web Developer, with 2+ years experience, looking to showcase my passion for building, maintaining, and enhancing websites from the ground up. I practice React/JavaScript, Ruby on Rails/MVC, and am excited to grow and develop in the tech field. As a fast learner who excels in a collaborative team environment, I know that I will be a great addition to the engineering team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Frameworks: Rails, Bootstrap

Software/ Tools: ReactJS, Test Driven Development, GitHub, Heroku

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL

API: RESTful

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer - Remote

January 2018-Present

 $Self\!-\!Employed~({\tt https://github.com/mbgrossm2009/my_portfolio})$

- Build, develop, and test websites based on client's specific needs.
- Construct reusable components to be used in interactive UI kits.
- Maintain and enhance existing websites with updated content and technologies.

Full Stack Web Developer - Remote

January 2018-January 2019

HathawayHomes-MA (https://github.com/mbgrossm2009/hathaway_homes)

- Designed and built a full-service real estate website with clean and organized code, in which users are able
 to customize their search based on a variety of categories such as geographical location, price point, number
 of rooms, and more.
- Constructed a PostgreSQL database which stores listings created by an Admin.
- Implemented the Zillow API using REST architecture.
- Installed and configured various AWS and Heroku tools.
- Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Heroku, AWS, TDD.

Full Stack Web Developer - Remote

March 2018-June 2018

 $ME \ \& \ FM \ Society \ of \ B.C \ (https://github.com/mbgrossm2009/MEFMApp)$

- Collaborated and developed a website, with a team, that allows patients to find the best doctor by searching a broad database
- Built comment section that allowed patients to engage and rate their experience.
- Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Heroku.

Assistant Manager - Wayland, MA

CVS Health

October 2015-Present July 2007-Present

- Resolved numerous customer complaints with great care and compassion.
- Recruited, interviewed and hired prospective candidates for open positions.
- Developed a schedule each week to guarantee staffing to operate store efficiently.
- Processed payroll to ensure employees were paid on time and correctly.
- Coached employees on performance level and opportunities for growth and improvement.

EDUCATION

Samex - Virtual

September 2018- December 2018

Worked with teammates to develop, test, and deploy websites for different clients.

Launch Academy - Virtual

March 2016-November 2017

Completed all core technical and career education requirements.

Curry College - Milton, MA

May 2009-May 2013

Bachelor of Arts, Information Technology.